Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rupalisupply-chain-procurement-expert (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Robotics

Transmission

Engineering

Certifications

Internal Auditor ISO 9001:2015, ISO 14001:2015 & ISO 45001:2018

Rupali Patil

Deputy Manager at Schindler India | Focusing on deep learning which will revolutionize the supply chain & procurement practices |Global Business Services, Contract Framing, SCM in Oil & Gas, GBS Procurement.

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Summary

I am a dynamic professional with proven capabilities in Material Controlling, Strategic Sourcing, Procurement, Supply Enhancement, and E-Auction Management

- ★ Working as a versatile expert for various organizations to provide services that are not only the best but legendary in every way
- ➤ WHERE CAN I ADD VALUE
- Managing float tender documents (RFQ) and offering clarity as required to vendors seeking quotations/proposals, while also regularly following up with suppliers to make sure prompt filing of offers
- Evaluating and endorsing suppliers' Engineering Procurement Manufacturing Schedule (EPMS)/ Work in the Engineering, Procurement, and Construction Industry (EPC).
- Extraordinary at reviewing vendor performance using a variety of factors such as rejection percentage, quality improvement rate, timely delivery, and credit terms.
- Excellently organizing Procure to Pay activities, strategic sourcing, supply enhancement, supply chain management, and electrical and instrumentation packages from overseas and domestic vendors for the Reliance Group's various business wings such as Defense, Power, and EPC Projects.
- Exceptional analytical evaluation experience to improve supply chain effectiveness, as well as evident competence in handling logistics functions.
- ➤ KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Coordinated Procure-to-Pay (P2P) Operations, Strategic Sourcing, Supply Chain Enhancement, and so on for Reliance Group's Defense, Power, and EPC Projects from Overseas and Domestic Vendors, Electrical and Instrumentation Packages.
- Utilized SPMAT and the SAP MM tool for material tracking and PR creation.
- Endorsed the Engineering, Procurement, and Construction (EPC) Business Supplier's Engineering, Procurement, and Manufacturing Schedule (EPMS) (EPC).

About Me

A supply chain specialist with strong database query skills setting a bar in a high-energy, often deadline-driven environment.

Do reach me out at: sankashti27@gmail.com

Experience

Schindler Group
Deputy Manager
June 2022 - Present (1 year 4 months)
Pune, Maharashtra, India

- Continually searching at spend analysis, dealing with 96% global and 4% zonal suppliers.
- Handling electronic components such as PCBs, COP, LOP, Batteries, UPS, Alarm panels, MCCB, and RCB.
- Entailed in the procurement of electronic parts for the elevator industry.
- Helping managers in making critical management procedures and operations decision making.
- ➤ Specialties: Material Controlling, Strategic Sourcing, Procurement, Supply Enhancement, and E-Auction Management

Accenture

Team Lead/Senior Procurement Specialist April 2020 - May 2022 (2 years 2 months) Pune, Maharashtra, India

 Contributed to the creation of intercompany and third-party purchase orders for MFG and Field plants.

- Willingly engaged in Projects APAC Region, working on projects for the countries of India, Brunei, Thailand, Myanmar, Malaysia, Singapore, and Bangladesh.
- Developing and implementing GR-IR reports.
- ➤ Specialties: Material Controlling, Strategic Sourcing, Procurement, Supply Enhancement, and E-Auction Management

Air Products

Material controller & Procurement February 2019 - April 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

- Managing gas supplies to BPCL in Kochi, Kerala; IOCL in Orissa; and SAIL in Bokaro, Bihar.
- Worked on projects involving gas (Jazan Saudi Arabia, LNG Canada, Uzbekistan, Russia).
- Established proposals (Pre-Bid estimation for different projects).
- Collaborated with the Engineering, Projects, and Product teams, as well as the Finance team, for GR-invoice clearing.

Reliance Infrastructure Manager-Lead Buyer September 2011 - January 2017 (5 years 5 months) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

- Supervised all Reliance Power, Mumbai Distribution & Transmission, EPC Business, and Defense Projects, as well as any other projects requiring electrical and instrumentation components by the Central Procurement Group.
- Completely liable for distributing requests for quotes (RFQ) documents to potential suppliers, as well as answering questions and clarifying specifications as needed to ensure on-time bid submission.
- Prepared tender documents and developed and kept standard contractual documentation and systems in conformance with equipment best practices.
- Attained goods like electrical and instrumentation gear essential to power, gas, engineering, procurement, and construction (EPC) projects).
- ➤ Specialties: Material Controlling, Strategic Sourcing, Procurement, Supply Enhancement, and E-Auction Management

Education

Veermata Jijabai Technological Institute (VJTI)

B.Tech, Electrical Engineering Technologies/Technicians · (2011)

WCE

Diploma, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (2008)